#### 81 BSS 81 BSS

### **Curriculum Vitae**

Last changed: 28.12.2018

D	Δ,	on	al	ч	Ωŧ	ail	le

Rafid Naif Misser 3 Iraq / Diwaniyah City 1001 Baghdad, Iraq Nationality: Iraq Marital status: Married No. of children: 3 Date of birth: 23.07.1974

E-mail address: rafidnaif@yahoo.com 07707860530 Tel (work) direct line: Tel (private): 07801006023 Tel (mobile): 009647707860530

#### Summary

From 2003 untill this date and in different locations I'm working with NGOs for different admin positions;

Finance officer, acting HR, procurement assistant manager, warehouse coordinator, and finaly as senior ogistics officer
from Aug.2003 to Dec.2006, I worked as finance officer with Mercy Coprs (NGO) and my responsibilities were:
Responsible of day to day of Financial needs of our office in coordination with programme and support
staff.  Prepare the required documentation of office and program payments according to MC standards
Li Sending Daily, Weekly and Monthly Financial Reports
Controlling and Responsible of Cash available in the Safe, staff salaries
From Jan. 2007 until Dec.2007, I got a new position in Kuwait country with Mercy Corps
n head qaurater office as Procurement Assistant Manager and my duties were:
Arranaging tendering process, to include – preparation of list of contractors, invitation letters, participate in
oid committee and bid analysis, comparison process, and finally the drafting of a contract for approved contractor
Responsible of day to day procurement needs of Kuwait office
Prepare the required documentation of supplies and transactions according to MC standards.
Ll Assist procurement Manager in preparation of monthly procurement reports and update database of
preferred contractors
Assist in preparation and tracking payments made to contractors and all procurement and contractors'
payments are properly filed in project files  I Management of projects' files systems in collaboration with programme manager and data tracking officer
- Management of projects filed systems in collaboration with programme manager and data tracking officer
From Jan.2008 to Oct.2010 I returned to Iraq also with Mercy Corps as Warehouse and
Distribution
Coordinator and the main responsibilities in this position were;  LI Implement and manage the warehouse in accordance with Standard Policy and Guidelines
Lipaily coordination of logistical, warehouse, and procurement activities;
LI Ensure the timely distribution of goods from the warehouse direct to entitled beneficiaries
L Preparation and submission of status reports on stock and issues/deliveries to main office
From Sep.2010 to Jun 2015 I'm working with NRC as Senior Logistics Officer and I'm the
first employee with
NRC in Iraq. My duties were;

# ne

*	Logistics	set	tup			
ı	1-					

L Ensure that logistics operations are in line with NRC's logistics policies and procedures and donor

\*Procurement & Purchasing

LI Ensure that effective procurement procedures are in place and followed in accordance with the NRC and donor Guidelines

L Develop and ensure that effective procedures are in place for storage and maintenance of all organisational assets, equipments and materials in accordance with NRC and donor Guidelines

\*Fleet Management

LI Ensure the functionality of the NRC vehicle fleet to support programme implementation

## From Jun 2015 to Nov 2017 I'm working with NRC as Logistics Coordinator. My duties were;

<ul> <li>Providing and supporting with all technical logistics for Baghdad staff and and other sub offices in Anbar and Salah Aldin staff.</li> </ul>
LI Ensure that logistics operations are in line with NRC's logistics policies and procedures and donor
requirements.
*Procurement & Purchasing
LI Ensure that effective procurement procedures are in place and followed in accordance with the NRC and donor Guidelines
* Warehouse
☐ Develop and ensure that effective procedures are in place for storage and maintenance of all organisational
assets, equipments and materials in accordance with NRC and donor Guidelines
*Fleet Management
☐ Ensure the functionality of the NRC vehicle fleet to support programme implementation
Of course there other many responsibilities under this position,
From Jul 2018 to Dec 2018 I'm working with TDH as Logistics Officer. My duties were;
<ul> <li>Providing and supporting with all technical logistics and fleet movement for Baghdad staff and Ana offices in Anbar.</li> </ul>
LI Ensure that logistics operations are in line with TDH logistics policies and procedures and donor
requirements.
*Fleet Management
Ensure the functionality of the TDH vehicle fleet to support programe implementation
☐ I was responsible for ICT requirements.
All related Asset inventory was under my responsibility.
University / Education college / English Department, Iraq / Qaddisiayh City / Qaddisiyah University
(Languages - College / University, Bachelor's degree)
In English Department we studied all the topics who is related to English language and we learned how to teach this
language in our school with intermidiat and secondary schools. Another good point that learning English language
had helped me in my work with NGOs for the 11 years that I worked with them, since English language is very
important and very helpful for the field work.  (Average grade: %60)
(Average grade: %00)
Logistics Coordinator, Norwegian Refugee Council (Sector:Other (describe), Specialization: Logistics,
Role: Manager executive)
The Logistics Coordinator is responsible for overall establishment and implementation of the NRC Logistics systems & procedures for the Iraq office. As logistics Coodinator I'm leading more than 35 staff (as employees
and local drivers). I'm responsible for many departments in Baghdad office. Beside Baghdad office I was leading
technically our 2 sub offices in Anbar city.
I'm responsible for all logistics and prourement duties. Also I'm responsible for transportation dept. and under this role I'm supervising more than 26 local drivers. I'm supervising IT staff. also I'm responsible for
all maintenance and fixing works for all all NRc equipments, assets and building (office, guesthouse and
warehouse spaces)
Senior Logistics Officer, Norwegian Refugee Council (Sector:Other (describe), Specialization: Logistics,
Role:Senior executive)
The Senior Logistics Officer is responsible for overall establishment and implementation of the NRC Logistics
systems & procedures for the Iraq office. As senior logistics officer; I'm responsible for many department in
the office. I'm responsible for all logistics and prourement duties. Also I'm responsible for transportation dept.
and under this role I'm supervising more than 10 local drivers. I'm supervising IT staff. also I'm responsible for
all maintenance and fixing works for all all NRc equipments, assets and building (office and guesthouse
spaces).

01.2008 - 10.2010

01.2011 - 06-2015

Education

Position

06.2015 - --->

10.1993 - 06.1998

 $\textbf{Warehouse and Distribution Coordinator}, \textbf{Mercy Corps} \ (\textbf{Sector:} \textit{Transport} \ / \ \textit{Distribution},$ 

Specialization: Transport / Distribution, Role: Supervisor)

Managing of Warehouses and Distribution Food Aids. I was responsible and controling the movement of the commodities (food Assistant) in the warhouse. I was responsible for the statuse of the commodities inside the warehouse under the the standard poloicy of warehousing. Beside this main job i was working as acting head office in our branch office. Sending daily, weekly and monthly reports to our main office.

01.2007 - 12.2007 Procurement Assistant Manager, Mercy Corps (Sector: Other (describe), Specialization: Operations, Role: Assistant) Controlling Procurement issues, Tenders, Purchases, Preparing Contracts, Selecting Companies according to Data base, ....etc. In this position I was working in Kuwait country and I was assisting my manager to control and leading the main works and duties for procurement field for our four offices in Irag. also I was working as logistics and procurement staff in Kuwait Head quarter office. 08.2003 - 12.2006 Finance Officer, Mercy Corps (Sector: Accounting, Specialization: Finance, Role: Supervisor) In this position I was responsible for all transactions and daily expenses in the office in coordination with program and support departments. Sending weekly and monthly financial reports to main office was the main role for me in this position and i was controling the filling system for finance documents and reports. 07.1999 - 11.2001 English Teacher, Schools and privet language Institutes (Sector:Educational, Specialization:Education / Training, Role:Other) I'm graduted from Education college, Englsih Department, that helped me to teach English language in many schools and privet institute for english and computer in Yemen Country under yearly contract with Education offices in Yemen cities. **Projects** 09.2013 - ---> Community Mobilization and Service Coordination, US Embassy (BPRM) In this project I'm in direct with program staff who are wr=orking under this project for arranging the meetings and activities. 03.2011 - 02.2014 Shelter Project, UNHABITAT I'm responsible in this project to arrange the transportation and movements of program staff and any other logistics requirements. 12.2009 - 12.2012 Camp management, UNHCR As logistics I'm responsible to provide program staff with all meeting supplies and renting meeting venues. 01.2008 - 10.2010 Distribution Food Aids, World Food Program My role in this project that to control the distribution of food aids to IDPs and manage the warehouse issues. 08.2003 - 12.2007 Camp management, USAID Under this project I got two jobs, Finance officer and Procurement Assistant manager Training/certifications Regional NRC Logistics Seminar, Norwegian Refugee Council 04.02.2013 - 06.02.2013 This training had been achieved in Jordan and covered many important topics in Logistics and Procurement Department like; \* Logistics Principles. \* Roles, responsibilities, communication and cooperation. \* standard Operation Procedures \* Procurement Procedures and Planning \* Warehousing Management\* \* Asset Management \* Vehicle Management and fleet Management \* Insurance Coverage \*Many other topics 04.05.2012 - 08.05.2012 First Aid training Course, Iraqi Red Crescent Society in Baghdad The First Aid Training course was concucted by the Iraqi Red Crescent in Baghdad. The following topics were covered: \*Scene Safety \*Recovery position \*Treatment of bleeding \*Use of "quick clot" \*Stabilization of broken limbs \*Basic burn injuries \*Calling the emergency services 05.10.2009 - 07.10.2009 Training, Training of Warehouse Management in Erbil, Irag This is the second training of warehouse mamagement but with skills and improving the work after the first training 24.03.2008 - 25.03.2008 Training, Training of Warehouse Management in Amman, Jordan For the position as warehouse Coordinator, I got this training in Amman and it was discussing all the main topics and skills on how to manage the warehouse and how to keep the commodity in the warehouse safe and in good 06.12.2004 - 08.12.2004 Training and Conference, Middle East Regional Finance Conference in Lebanon This Conference was discussing the main financial topics of Donors and how we got money from donors. This Conference was very important because it was discuusing the main duties, challenges ands skills of the four countries in the middle east. Workshop, USAID CAP Conference in Amman, Jordan 11.10.2004 - 12.10.2004 The conference was about the main issues and policies of our work with CAP project which was donated by USAID.

01.08.2003 - 08.08.2004

Training, Finance Skills and procedurs

- \*This is the first training that I got in Mercy Corps Organization as a first job with NGOs and it covered the following topics:
- \*Learning all the finance skills, procedures and how to apply Donar policies.
- \* How to control the daily transactions (cash Advances, direct payments,....)
- \*Sending daily, weekly and monthly reports to main office.
- \* How to control and how to deal with cash in safe and how to bnmake cash count.

#### 17.07.2004 - 21.07.2004

#### Training, Leadership and Management Skills Training

With Mercy Corps I got this training in Amman and it was very useful and important training. \* It was concentrating on main and strong skills of leadership and how to manage the work in the field or in the office. \* The other main topic in this training is how to lead and how to improve your relationship with the employees either under your supervision or with same level or our supervisors

#### 21.04.2004 - 23.04.2004

#### Training, Finance officers' workshop

Learning more skills about finance field in Mercy Corps.

- \* Revision Donar Procedures and Policies and how to apply them.
- \* Developing the financial work of the officers.
- \* How to improve the relation between the finance staff and program staff.
- \* Improving the financial reports that we send to Head quarter office.

#### Language

Arabic Oral: Excellent. Written: Excellent English Oral: Good. Written: Good

#### Keywords / additional info

- \* Good Experience and knowledge with Logistics and procurement field
- \* I can chieve my work under limited supervision
- \* Under workload and pressure I can work with unlimited hours in order to finish my work in time
- \* Very good knowledge with Microsoft office skills
- \* I have good ability to deal with reports and making SOPs
- \* Flexible and friendly with staff under my supervision to implemnt very successful work
- \* Decision maker with studied plan
- \* Innovative and creative
- \* Accountable and loyal to to achieve the goals and decisions
- \* Adhers to organization secuirty regulations and plans
- \* I have no problem to travel between offices to control the works

#### References

After accepting my CV and on demand

#### Ideal job

Sector Emergency Relief

Special fieldLogisticsRoleSupervisorLocationIraqType of jobFull time

Travel travelling with human operations must be expected